If you're using Microsoft Intune to manage your devices differently, one of the roles you
will perform in using Microsoft Intune is actually managing your device update.
So as you may know, we have the configuration manager, and also we have the Microsoft Intune.
Some other small amount of company, I'm working for as a consultant, we have configuration
manager, which is being used to deploy updates to all the devices and the company worldwide,
but we have Microsoft Intune, which is actually being used to deploy policies to the device.
So now we now apply what we call the core manager using both Microsoft Intune and the
configuration manager.
But if, for example, you want to use all the Microsoft Intune to deploy update to all
your devices and not your configuration manager, you will do the following.
But in this environment, I've already configured the Windows Server of this service to deploy
updates to all my devices, but at the same time, I want to show you how to use the Microsoft
Intune to deploy updates to devices.
So what we need to do is to go to devices, and from here, we need to just scroll down.
And you can see we have, on our policies, you can see we have the, of the things for Windows
10, and later, we have future updates for Windows 10 and later, we have quality updates
for Windows 10 and later, and also we have updates for iOS and Mac OS.
So let's go for the updates for Windows 10 later.
So if you have been using the SCCM before in the past, definitely you'll be familiar
with how to create updates, which of course for you is going to be straightforward and
very easy.
So this is your first time of doing this, I used to watch on this video, you just click
create profile, and I'm just called these updates ring, just an example name, you got the
key, just write it description, created by Colvin Johnson, and then we can now click
Nest.
Here, you can see this is Microsoft of product update, you're going to see allow Windows
drivers, you got all the block, or say allow.
So you want to have quality update, the file period dates, that is what makes it set to
zero, we got to let it put it to five days, and here you can see since the file quality
update for the specific number of days, and also for the future update, you can just put
it for five.
So upgrade Windows 10 to the devices to a later Windows 11, if you want to upgrade your
Windows 10, you can pull days to yes, but at this point, we just want to only install
updates to Windows 10, the devices, set feature updates on the stop period to, we can't
really, you can see it's set to 10, but you can't let them modify it.
So here, when you're nice, cool that you can see we have some automotive kitchen, like
for example, the active hours, that's from 8,000, and ends by 5,000, we have to let
change this if we went, and also says auto install admin 10 last time, you can auto install
our start admin 10 last time, regardless your sales auto install it, but the last time
with me is the user, we not to fight if the device need to restart and the user can't
rally.
So okay, I want to restart my device or skip the, the restart, but mind you, skipping
a restart, actually, doesn't go forever, because when you skip the restart, attach
some title device before to start.
So use deadline settings deadline for future update, as you allow, we can set a try to
add a configure deadline.
This is auto reboot before deadline onto a solid, you can't say yes.
And then after doing all these, we need to click next, but I'm going to see if, okay,
there is very error message, so that was, so error message, and I will kind of click next.
And then here you can see says, add all devices, or can add a group, we can just have
to add all devices, which of course is not advisable, but you can add a group and just
create a specific group, and then include that group in to this other group.
For example, you have your Windows 10, or for example, a test group, which wants to test
the update submission, everything goes well, according to plan before it's been distributed
to all your devices worldwide, so let's just click next, and then we cannot click create.
Mind you, I didn't deploy this update to the devices, why, because I'm using the Windows
totally deployed update to my devices, so I don't want to cause any conflicts, that is
a reason why, I just show you how to do it without deploying it to any group or to all
my devices.